There's no doubt that one of the greatest achievements by humankind is the exploration of space.
毫无疑问，人类最伟大的成就之一就是太空探索。
Ever since cosmonaut Yuri Gagarin became the first person to journey into space in 1961, scientists have been exploring it and pushing the boundaries to try and go further and discover things that are yet to be discovered.
自1961年苏联宇航员尤里·加加林成为首位进入太空的人类以来，科学家们就一直在探索太空，不断突破极限，试图走得更远，发现那些尚未被发现的事物。
But probably the only thing that's certain about this exploration into the unknown so far, is it's been dominated by men.
但到目前为止，关于这场未知探索，唯一可以确定的可能是：它一直由男性主导。
Of course, in the past, women haven't been excluded from space projects.
当然，在过去，女性并未被排除在太空项目之外。
Women have been involved on the ground at mission control – and behind the scenes women have worked as seamstresses, stitching vital spaceflight components.
女性曾参与地面任务控制工作——在幕后，她们担任缝纫工，缝制关键的太空飞行部件。
In fact, many of NASA's key missions would never have left the ground without them.
事实上，美国国家航空航天局（NASA）的许多重要任务如果没有她们，根本无法顺利开展。
And it was a group of black female mathematicians, recently depicted in a Hollywood movie called Hidden Figures, who helped NASA launch an American into space.
而且，正是一群黑人女性数学家（她们的故事最近被改编成好莱坞电影《隐藏人物》）帮助NASA将美国人送入了太空。
But this hasn't been women's only contribution.
但这并非女性唯一的贡献。
Back in 1963, Soviet cosmonaut Valentina Tereshkova became the first woman to blast off into space.
早在1963年，苏联宇航员瓦莲京娜·捷列什科娃就成为首位飞向太空的女性。
However, after that, space flight programmes were slow to employ women.
然而，在那之后，太空飞行项目在聘用女性方面进展缓慢。
In the USA, NASA didn't accept applications from women to become astronauts until 1978 and as missions to the Moon had ended by then, it meant Neil Armstrong's arrival on the Moon in 1969 was 'a giant step for mankind' – and also an important step for a man.
在美国，NASA直到1978年才开始接受女性宇航员的申请，而当时登月任务已经结束，这意味着1969年尼尔·阿姆斯特朗登上月球的壮举，既是“人类的一大步”——也是男性的重要一步。
But attitudes have moved on and leading engineers at NASA have said that the first person to set foot on Mars should be a woman.
但人们的态度已经发生了转变，NASA的顶尖工程师表示，首位踏上火星的人应该是女性。
The space agency aims to have a gender-balanced workforce but can only achieve that if equal numbers of men and women train for science and technology careers.
该航天机构致力于打造性别均衡的员工队伍，但要实现这一目标，需要有同等数量的男性和女性投身科技领域的职业培训。
As Allison McIntryre, Chief of the NASA Space Vehicle Mock-up Facility, told the BBC: "My director is a women, my former division chief is a woman. We have female astronauts.
正如NASA太空飞行器模型设施负责人艾莉森·麦金太尔在接受BBC采访时所说：“我的主管是女性，我之前的部门主管也是女性。
We haven't put a woman on the Moon yet.
我们有女性宇航员，但还没有把女性送上月球。
And I think that perhaps the first person to step on Mars should be a woman."
我认为，或许首位踏上火星的人应该是女性。”
A woman landing on Mars would be an incredible achievement for being a first for womankind and would, for some, be out of this world!
女性登陆火星将是一项非凡的成就——这女性来说，这是首次，对一些人来说，更是令人惊叹的突破！
It would certainly inspire a younger female generation by showing what is possible.
这无疑会向年轻一代女性展示无限可能。
For them, the thought of other planets being a men-only destination, would be an alien concept.
对她们而言，其他行星是男性专属目的地的想法，将会是一个完全陌生的概念。